Donna C. Stimpson Collection GLBTQ.2012.05
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
Donna C. Stimpson Collection
1987-2011
GLBTQ.2012.05
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
2.0 Linear feet
Donna Stimpson has been an activist for GLBTQ rights including domestic partnership benefits, same sex marriage, gender equality, and second parent adoption in Connecticut and nationally. She has been involved with several equality groups and continues to work in the state for civil rights. The collection includes some of her personal documents as well as newspaper and internet articles, publications, memorabilia, and general information spanning over a few decades.
Stimpson, Donna C.
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
Donna Stimpson, a Planning Analyst Specialist for the State of Connecticut in the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services in Hartford, has been an avid activist for GLBTQ civil rights in the state. From serving as President (and then board member) of the National Organization of Women, CT Chapter to fighting for domestic partnership benefits for state employees and same sex marriage legislation to participating in several events for equal rights in Connecticut and nationwide, Stimpson is an important figure in Connecticut GLBTQ history. There are several materials from other organizations included in the collection such as Love Makes A Family (LMF), a grassroots political and educational organization that works for same sex marriage equality. When the law finally passed in 2008 in Connecticut, a year later on December 31, 2009, LMF felt it had completed its marriage equality work and ceased operation. Another group, Connecticut Chapter of the National Organization for Women (CT NOW), strives to impact and change attitudes, beliefs, and policies that harm all women by fighting for political, economic, and social justice through education and action. Lambda Legal, founded in 1973, is the oldest and largest legal organization in the nation dedicated to the full recognition of the civil rights of lesbians, gay men, bisexuals, transgendered people, and people with HIV and AIDS. Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Education Network, Connecticut Chapter (GLSEN) works to ensure safe schools for all students, regardless of sexual orientation and gender identity through teacher training and public policy. There are over 40 Chapters around the country, which work closely with the national staff of GLSEN to implement programs, and to keep national staff informed of local events.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains a variety of publications, correspondence, newspaper and internet articles, and general information relating to gay and lesbian culture, same-sex marriage legislation, second parent adoption legislation, Connecticut state employee domestic partnership rights among other related issues. The material dates from 1987-2011.
Stimpson, Donna; Child development; Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights; Connecticut Stonewall Foundation; connecticut womens rights; Gay couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Gay liberation movement -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Hate crimes -- Connecticut -- Legislative history; Homosexuality -- Connecticut -- Periodicals; Homosexuality -- Families; Homosexuality -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Periodicals; Same-sex marriage -- Connecticut; Unmarried couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Connecticut
- Donna Stimpson- Letter to the Editor (The Record Journal), several written drafts, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Donna Stimpson- Correspondence (political), 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Donna Stimpson- Correspondence (personal), 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- CT State Employees- Domestic Partnership Benefit information, newspaper clippings, correspondence, Donna Stimpson personal testimony, 1999-2001; 2008. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CT State Employees- Agendas/notes from meetings, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CT State Employees- Domestic Partnership Benefits- Legislation, Memorandums, and legal forms, 1999; 2002; 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CT State Employees- STATE PRIDE organization- Membership forms, press release, organization information, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CT State Employees- STATE PRIDE organization- Email correspondence, event information, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CT State Employees- Binding Arbitration notes, October 28-29, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Administrative and Residual (A&R) Convention- Continue support of domestic partnership benefits, April 28, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Second Parent Adoption/ DOMA Amendment- April-June, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Same Sex Marriage- “How to” guides on lobbying, writing letters to politicians, etc., DOMA introduction to House of Representatives, fact sheets, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Same Sex Marriage- Public events, testimonies, newspaper articles, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Same Sex Marriage- Legislation, newspaper articles, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Same Sex Marriage-Newspaper articles, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Same Sex Marriage- Newspaper articles, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Same Sex Marriage- Newspaper articles, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Same Sex Marriage- Newspaper articles, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Love Makes A Family- flyers, Congressional District, House, and Senate lists, legislative alerts, testimonials, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Love Makes A Family- Meetings, flyers, correspondence, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Love Makes A Family- E-mail correspondence, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Love Makes A Family- E-mail correspondence, Hartford Rally, flyers, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Love Makes A Family- Annual report, announcements, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Love Makes A Family- Announcements, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Love Makes A Family- 2006 Annual Report, rally announcement, ceasing operation letter, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (NGLTF)- Equality Begins at Home- Campaign information, events, CT rainbow flag raising, meeting agendas, correspondence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- NGLTF- “To Have and to Hold: Organizing for Our Right to Marry”, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- National Organization for Women (NOW)- Correspondence, events, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- National Organization for Women (NOW)- Lesbian rights newsletter fact sheets, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- National Organization for Women (NOW)- Lesbian Rights Summit, Washington D.C. (April 1999)- Correspondence, newspaper, program, 1999; Women of Color and Allies Summit (June 1999)- Registration form. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Connecticut National Organization for Women (CTNOW)-Correspondence, Congressional District surveys, meeting minutes, 1996-2003 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- “The Legal Rights of Lesbian and Gay Men in Connecticut” booklets, 1995, 1997, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc.- Resource list, memos, testimony, membership booklet, documents about marriage, 1995; articles, 2005. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- True Colors, Inc.- Safe Harbor Project- Collaboration between Department of Children & Families (DCF), CT Association of Foster & Adoptive Parents (CAFAP), and True Colors to address the needs of LGBT youth: Foster parents recruitment, mentoring, training, etc., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- True Colors, Inc.- Announcements, correspondence, events, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- True Colors, Inc.- Diversity training materials, Announcements, correspondence, events, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Gay & Lesbian Advocates and Defenders (GLAD)-“Legal Planning for Same-Sex Couples”, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- GLAD- Newsletter, mailings, 1997-2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Education Network, Connecticut Chapter (GLSEN CT)- E-mail correspondence, weekly newsletters, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- GLSEN CT- Weekly newsletters, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgendere Civil Rights (CLGBTCR)- Meeting minutes, press releases, fact sheets about legislation, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- CCLGBTCR- Events, correspondence, meeting minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- CCLGBTCR- Events, correspondence, announcements, events, Diversity Project Focus Group Report, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- CCLGBTCR- Events, correspondence, announcements, newspaper articles, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- GLBTQ and Education- Correspondence, articles of events at universities & high schools, Children from the Shadows program for youth. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Human Rights Campaign- “Wedded to Intolerance” Special Report, related articles, announcements about legislation, 1996, 1999, 2002, 2003, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Connecticut Stonewall Foundation/Congress- Event flyers, Timeline project, notes, budget proposals, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- National Center for Lesbian Rights (NCLR)- Current legal cases, event flyers, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- NCLR- E-newsletter, 2003; Lesbian Rights Committee e-mail correspondence, 1999. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- “Queer and Active” Group- Email correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Connecticut Women’s Education and Legal Fund (CWEALF)- Spring Awards Dinner, May 1996, Pridelink: A Resource Guide of LGBT Organizations, correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Connecticut Citizen Action Group (CCAG)- Newsletter, membership information, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- National Coming Out Day- October 11, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Adult Identity Development: The Heart of Recovery- Notes, Rutgers, June 1996. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Same Sex Marriage- Vermont- Articles, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Same Sex Marriage- Massachusetts, Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Same Sex Marriage- California and Hawaii- Articles, 1999-2008 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Same Sex Marriage- Washington, DC, Oregon, Illinois, Tennessee, Pennsylvania, Colorado, Ohio, New York- Articles, 1996-2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Same Sex Marriage- International- Articles, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Various E-mail Event Alerts, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- GLBTQ and religion- Articles, pamphlets, booklets, 1992-1996; 2000-2002; 2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- GLBTQ and the arts- Museum articles, internet articles, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Gay parenting and families- Journal/book excerpts, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Connecticut Law Journal- “Gay and Lesbian Law Students Association at the University of Connecticut School of Law v. Board of Trustees, University of Connecticut”, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Connecticut Universities & Activism- Event flyers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Tenth Connecticut Annual Gay & Lesbian Film Festival- Program, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Discrimination/Hate Crimes- Articles, legislation, 1995-2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- AFL-CIO- Union correspondence, Annual Report, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence from Girl Scouts, Alumni letter- Analyze impact of being a Girl Scout on women’s lives, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Heterosexual questionnaire, 1995; Health and Social Services Needs Survey, 2001. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Timeline of GLBTQ Events, 1900-1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- “Issues in Counseling Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Adolescents” Scott L Hershberger & Anthony R. D’Augelli, 225-247, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 1999, part 2. (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Newspapers and Internet Articles- GLBTQ politics, culture, rights, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Miscellaneous documents and items. (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Lesbian Culture: An Anthology by Julia Penelope & Susan Wolfe ed., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- “Unity Through Diversity” T-Shirt. Connecticut Pride, June 20, 1998. “Love Makes A Family” poster Bag of pins, magnets (marriage equality, civil rights, aids awareness), aids awareness ribbon, and marriage equality bracelet (Box 3)